<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://marines.dev/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://marines.dev/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-11-03T10:59:07-05:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MARINE CODERS</title><subtitle>Marine Coders - #AnyMarineACoder</subtitle><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><entry><title type="html">MIU Marine Coders FY23 Recruiting - Reserves</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/MIU-FY23-Recruiting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MIU Marine Coders FY23 Recruiting - Reserves" /><published>2022-10-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/MIU-FY23-Recruiting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/MIU-FY23-Recruiting/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-miu-marine-coders-reserve-opportunity-only-and-contribute-to-critical-missions-as-a-software-developer-data-architect-or-designer&quot;&gt;Join MIU Marine Coders (reserve opportunity only) and contribute to critical missions as a software developer, data architect, or designer!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;fy23-applications-are-open-through-11-november-2022&quot;&gt;FY23 Applications are open through 11 November 2022&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://20210826173501_9th2w6eav43dzwba.applytojob.com/apply/W73XeRgThy/FY23-MIU-Application-all-Branches-All-Positions&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--info&quot;&gt;Apply Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Marine Innovation Unit 600x600.png&quot; alt=&quot;MIU&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-application-now-consists-of-two-parts&quot;&gt;The application now consists of two parts:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apply at the link above and select &lt;em&gt;ILB-Software Data&lt;/em&gt; for the “What is your third preference for Branch / role in the unit?” drop down&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An email with supplemental documents
 (Note: the application is not complete and will not be considered without both parts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;application-window-17-oct-22-through-11-nov-22-2359et&quot;&gt;Application window: 17 Oct 22 through 11 Nov 22 (2359ET)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MIU Talent Board: 17-20 Nov 22&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Board Results Notification: no later than 2 Dec 22&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If selected, they will be expected to join MIU NLT 15 January 2023,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attend one virtual 1/2-day training session be ready for AT: 
21 Jan 2023, 1000-1400ET (Saturday) or 
24 Jan 2023, 1900-2300ET (Tuesday)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attend annual training, likely in Quantico, VA, from 5-12 March 2023 (including travel)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Join MIU Marine Coders (reserve opportunity only) and contribute to critical missions as a software developer, data architect, or designer! FY23 Applications are open through 11 November 2022</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Marine Innovation Unit Partnership and Rebranding!</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/MIU-Partnership-Rebranding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Marine Innovation Unit Partnership and Rebranding!" /><published>2022-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/MIU-Partnership-Rebranding</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/MIU-Partnership-Rebranding/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/press/marinecoders_banner.png&quot; alt=&quot;Marine Coders Rebrand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marine Coders is excited to announce that it has officially partnered with Marine Innovation Unit (MIU) to form the MIU Marine Coders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This team will coordinate bringing on reserve software developers as a force provider for software activities and programs in the Marine Corps. We believe that these developers will be a game changer to create a better, more lethal Marine Corps. These positions are rank and MOS agnostic, meaning anyone with the right technical experience can make a difference. The partnership with MIU will advance both MIU and Marine Coder’s mission sets. We are proud to offer 2 reserve Selected Marine Corps Reserve (SMCR) positions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miu.applytojob.com/apply/SARAyhWg6O/Marine-Coders-Full-Stack-Developer-Status-Open&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--info&quot;&gt;Marine Coders Full Stack Software Developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://miu.applytojob.com/apply/EgDlyYoaAO/Data-Scientist-Status-Open&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--info&quot;&gt;Marine Coders Data Scientist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This partnership will bring a few changes to the Marine Coders. First, this partnership cements the Marine Coders concept into the Marine Corps through official billets assigned to the Marine Coders. This is a huge step forward for Marine Coders from unofficial concept to official organization. As such, we’ve decided to rebrand our logo to showcase this. Second, this partnership allows us to move from an active duty centric model to a full range of employment through the reserves. We are excited with what we can accomplish in 2022 and beyond. Third, MIU Marine Coders will work under a force provider model. We believe this will allow us to accelerate existing efforts through the directed application of software developers who understand industry best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A special thank you to Major Jim Carlson for making this a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is this in-person or remote?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are committed to employing the best talent we can find in support of the United States Marine Corps. Therefore, we are offering 80% remote work as part of the MIU Marine Coders, with the 20% being Annual Training (AT) and in person travel, only when required for mission success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do drill weekends work in MIU Marine Coders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;MIU offers remote drill weekends, split up over the entire month. While this depends on the specific project you will be working under, you can expect to work an average of 4 hours per week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What will I be working on at MIU Marine Coders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Software! Typing, moving, and communicating. We will ensure that you spend as much time as possible actually doing what you’re good at and solving problems, rather than spending time waiting for your computer to start up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the mission of the Marine Innovation Unit?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Marine Innovation Unit (MIU) leverages existing Marine talent to address advanced technology challenges in order to accelerate the development of new capabilities. More information about the unit and other open billets can be found at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marforres.marines.mil/MIU/&quot;&gt;MIU website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Marine Coders is excited to announce that it has officially partnered with Marine Innovation Unit (MIU) to form the MIU Marine Coders. This team will coordinate bringing on reserve software developers as a force provider for software activities and programs in the Marine Corps. We believe that these developers will be a game changer to create a better, more lethal Marine Corps. These positions are rank and MOS agnostic, meaning anyone with the right technical experience can make a difference. The partnership with MIU will advance both MIU and Marine Coder’s mission sets. We are proud to offer 2 reserve Selected Marine Corps Reserve (SMCR) positions. Marine Coders Full Stack Software Developer Marine Coders Data Scientist This partnership will bring a few changes to the Marine Coders. First, this partnership cements the Marine Coders concept into the Marine Corps through official billets assigned to the Marine Coders. This is a huge step forward for Marine Coders from unofficial concept to official organization. As such, we’ve decided to rebrand our logo to showcase this. Second, this partnership allows us to move from an active duty centric model to a full range of employment through the reserves. We are excited with what we can accomplish in 2022 and beyond. Third, MIU Marine Coders will work under a force provider model. We believe this will allow us to accelerate existing efforts through the directed application of software developers who understand industry best practices. A special thank you to Major Jim Carlson for making this a reality. FAQ Is this in-person or remote? We are committed to employing the best talent we can find in support of the United States Marine Corps. Therefore, we are offering 80% remote work as part of the MIU Marine Coders, with the 20% being Annual Training (AT) and in person travel, only when required for mission success. How do drill weekends work in MIU Marine Coders? MIU offers remote drill weekends, split up over the entire month. While this depends on the specific project you will be working under, you can expect to work an average of 4 hours per week. What will I be working on at MIU Marine Coders? Software! Typing, moving, and communicating. We will ensure that you spend as much time as possible actually doing what you’re good at and solving problems, rather than spending time waiting for your computer to start up. What is the mission of the Marine Innovation Unit? The Marine Innovation Unit (MIU) leverages existing Marine talent to address advanced technology challenges in order to accelerate the development of new capabilities. More information about the unit and other open billets can be found at the MIU website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Uniformed Developer Phoenix Cast</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Uniformed-Developer-Phoenix-Cast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uniformed Developer Phoenix Cast" /><published>2022-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Uniformed-Developer-Phoenix-Cast</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Uniformed-Developer-Phoenix-Cast/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Checkout the latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/phoenix-cast/id1508967644?i=1000551075629&quot;&gt;Phoenix Cast&lt;/a&gt; that highlights great work from uniformed developers and advocates for professionalizing capability development in the United States Marine Corps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Checkout the latest Phoenix Cast that highlights great work from uniformed developers and advocates for professionalizing capability development in the United States Marine Corps!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge DVIDS Article</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-DVIDS-Article/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge DVIDS Article" /><published>2021-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-DVIDS-Article</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-DVIDS-Article/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d1ldvf68ux039x.cloudfront.net/thumbs/photos/2110/6903472/1000w_q95.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Marine Coder LCpl Crum with Gen Matos, CIO, USMC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Brig. Gen. Joseph Matos, Director, Information, Command, Control Communications and Computers (IC4) presents an award to members of the I MEF Coding Team as the victor of the inaugural Micro-Application Development Innovation Challenge at the Pentagon in Arlington, Va., Aug. 27, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dvids-just-released-an-article-highlighting-the-20-active-duty-marine-coders-that-participated-in-the-2021-micro-application-innovation-challenge&quot;&gt;DVIDS just released an article highlighting the 20+ Active Duty Marine Coders that participated in the 2021 Micro-Application Innovation Challenge.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Marine Expeditionary Force (MEF) Coding Team’s readiness application was selected the winner of the inaugural Micro-Application Development Innovation Challenge formally announced via MARADMIN number 600/21, Oct. 19, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I MEF Coding Team’s readiness application leveraged the Marine Corps Business Operations Support Services (MCBOSS) Development-Security-Operations (DevSecOps) ecosystem to rapidly create a data comprehension and visualization tool called the Global Combat Support System Marine Corps (GCSS-MC) Reconciliation Operations Organization Tool (GROOT), drastically reducing the time and effort required by Marines to understand and report on readiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Micro-Application Innovation Challenge was announced via MARADMIN 164/21 on March 25, 2021 requesting each MEF to assemble a coding team, regardless of rank or military occupational specialty (MOS), to research, engineer, test and deploy a micro-software application to optimize operations.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dvidshub.net/news/407879/mef-wins-micro-app-innovation-challenge-against-coders-across-marine-corps&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--info btn--large&quot;&gt;Read More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge Winner!</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-Winner/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge Winner!" /><published>2021-10-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-Winner</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-Winner/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-are-excited-to-announce-that-i-mef-and-their-gccs-reconciliation-tool-groot-is-the-winner-of-the-2021-marine-coder-innovation-challenge&quot;&gt;We are excited to announce that I MEF and their GCCS Reconciliation Tool (GROOT) is the winner of the 2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competition was tough and picking a winner was a very difficult for the voting panel. II MEF’s Command Data Visualization Tool and III MEF’s Marine Logistics Planning Tool (MLPT) put up a great fight.  Checkout &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marines.mil/News/Messages/Messages-Display/Article/2815694/2021-inaugural-micro-application-development-innovation-challenge-results/&quot;&gt;MARADMIN 600/21&lt;/a&gt; for more details. GROOT is live and can be accessed via CAC at https://groot.apps.stg.mach9.usmc.mil/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge proved that given the tools, environments, resources, and time, Marines CAN:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build full stack, cloud native web applications ready for deployment to the organization’s network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Effectively navigate all six steps of the Risk Management Framework (RMF) methodology to achieve an authority to Operate (ATO) in just ~90 days!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Execute Git Flow and Trunk Based Development to successfully build and collaborate on a product as a team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leverage a Platform as a Service (PaaS) to build containerized apps using a DevSecOps pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And much more…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thank you to all that supported the challenge throughout the 4 months, to include but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DC I C4 for their sponsorship of the initiative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MCBOSS Infrastructure and Platform teams for providing cloud hosted PaaS supporting each team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MCBOSS Apps for their project management and RMF support for each application&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The individual teams and their leadership for allowing them to work on this challenge in addition their assigned Marine Corps duties!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future is bright for uniformed coders in the United States Marine Corps!!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">We are excited to announce that I MEF and their GCCS Reconciliation Tool (GROOT) is the winner of the 2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge! The competition was tough and picking a winner was a very difficult for the voting panel. II MEF’s Command Data Visualization Tool and III MEF’s Marine Logistics Planning Tool (MLPT) put up a great fight. Checkout MARADMIN 600/21 for more details. GROOT is live and can be accessed via CAC at https://groot.apps.stg.mach9.usmc.mil/</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge Voting Panel Selection Day</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-Voting-Panel-Day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge Voting Panel Selection Day" /><published>2021-08-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-08-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-Voting-Panel-Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-Voting-Panel-Day/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;today-marks-the-completion-of-the-2021-marine-coder-innovation-challenge--the-three-mef-teams-will-brief-the-enterprise-voting-panel-this-morning-and-a-challenge-winner-will-be-selected&quot;&gt;Today marks the completion of the 2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge!  The three MEF teams will brief the enterprise voting panel this morning, and a challenge winner will be selected!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A huge thank you to all that supported the challenge throughout the 4 months, to include but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DC I C4 for their sponsorship of the initiative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MCBOSS Infrastructure and Platform teams for providing cloud hosted PaaS supporting each team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MCBOSS Apps for their project management and Risk Management Framework support for each application&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The individual teams and their leadership for allowing them to work on this challenge in addition their assigned Marine Corps duties!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next post will announce the winner!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Today marks the completion of the 2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge! The three MEF teams will brief the enterprise voting panel this morning, and a challenge winner will be selected! A huge thank you to all that supported the challenge throughout the 4 months, to include but not limited to: DC I C4 for their sponsorship of the initiative MCBOSS Infrastructure and Platform teams for providing cloud hosted PaaS supporting each team MCBOSS Apps for their project management and Risk Management Framework support for each application The individual teams and their leadership for allowing them to work on this challenge in addition their assigned Marine Corps duties!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge Proposal Selection</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-Proposal-Selection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge Proposal Selection" /><published>2021-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-Proposal-Selection</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge-Proposal-Selection/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;four-projects-were-selected-for-further-development-in-the-marine-corps-business-operations-support-services-mcboss-accredited-devsecops-environment&quot;&gt;Four projects were selected for further development in the Marine Corps Business Operations Support Services (MCBOSS) accredited DevSecOps environment!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selected proposals are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I MEF: GCCS Reconciliation Tool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;II MEF: Command Data Visualization Tool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;III MEF: REDONKULATOR Logistics Planning Tool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MARFORRES: Predictive Maintenance Operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each MEF team will begin a 90 day development evolution where they will learn how to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plan and execute agile software development methodology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Achieve an Authority to Operate (ATO) through the Risk Management Framework (RMF) methodology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Git Flow and Trunk Based Development to effectively build and collaborate on a product as a team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leverage a Platform as a Service (PaaS) to build containerized apps using a DevSecOps pipeline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build a web hosted static site!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And much more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Four projects were selected for further development in the Marine Corps Business Operations Support Services (MCBOSS) accredited DevSecOps environment! The selected proposals are: I MEF: GCCS Reconciliation Tool II MEF: Command Data Visualization Tool III MEF: REDONKULATOR Logistics Planning Tool MARFORRES: Predictive Maintenance Operations</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 Marine Coder Innovation Challenge" /><published>2021-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/Marine-Coder-Innovation-Challenge/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;calling-all-mefsthe-time-is-now-to-bring-together-all-your-coding-talent-to-create-a-micro-application-in-an-accredited-marine-corps-devsecops-environment--see-software-innovation-challenge-maradmin-for-details&quot;&gt;Calling all MEFs…The time is now to bring together all your coding talent to create a micro-application in an accredited Marine Corps DevSecOps environment.  See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marines.mil/News/Messages/Messages-Display/Article/2549693/solicitation-for-participation-in-the-marine-corps-inaugural-micro-application/&quot;&gt;Software Innovation Challenge MARADMIN&lt;/a&gt; for details!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Situation: This MARADMIN serves as an announcement of the first micro- application development innovation challenge.  IC4 requests each MEF to assemble, and authorize the duty efforts of, one Coding Team from their cadre of technically skilled personnel to research, engineer, test, and deploy a micro-software application that will either reduce operational friction, optimize workflow, increase Unit Readiness, or alleviate administrative burdens across any warfighting function.  MEF Coding Teams will be authorized to utilize Marine Corps resources such as time, equipment, and facilities. Furthermore, the MEF Coding Teams will utilize the Marine Corps Business Optimization Support Services (MCBOSS) Development-Security-Operations (DevSecOps) ecosystem to rapidly develop software in support of the challenge.  This challenge tests the theory that, given the right resources, talented Marines across the MOS spectrum can design and deliver software capabilities that can enable and expand efficiencies from tactical to strategic level.  IC4 recommends that the Marine Expeditionary Force Information Group take the lead within their respective MEF to assemble and lead the MEF’s Coding Team in support of this challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Calling all MEFs…The time is now to bring together all your coding talent to create a micro-application in an accredited Marine Corps DevSecOps environment. See Software Innovation Challenge MARADMIN for details! Situation: This MARADMIN serves as an announcement of the first micro- application development innovation challenge. IC4 requests each MEF to assemble, and authorize the duty efforts of, one Coding Team from their cadre of technically skilled personnel to research, engineer, test, and deploy a micro-software application that will either reduce operational friction, optimize workflow, increase Unit Readiness, or alleviate administrative burdens across any warfighting function. MEF Coding Teams will be authorized to utilize Marine Corps resources such as time, equipment, and facilities. Furthermore, the MEF Coding Teams will utilize the Marine Corps Business Optimization Support Services (MCBOSS) Development-Security-Operations (DevSecOps) ecosystem to rapidly develop software in support of the challenge. This challenge tests the theory that, given the right resources, talented Marines across the MOS spectrum can design and deliver software capabilities that can enable and expand efficiencies from tactical to strategic level. IC4 recommends that the Marine Expeditionary Force Information Group take the lead within their respective MEF to assemble and lead the MEF’s Coding Team in support of this challenge.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">II MIG Marine Coders Cell</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/II-MIG-Cell-Established/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="II MIG Marine Coders Cell" /><published>2021-02-09T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-02-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/II-MIG-Cell-Established</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/II-MIG-Cell-Established/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;ii-mig-marine-coders-cell-established&quot;&gt;II MIG Marine Coders Cell Established!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-ii-mig-co-colonel-russell-signed-the-ii-mig-marine-coder-charter-today-effectively-establishing-the-first-marine-coder-cell-in-the-fleet-marine-force&quot;&gt;The II MIG CO, Colonel Russell, signed the II MIG Marine Coder charter today effectively establishing the first Marine Coder Cell in the Fleet Marine Force.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cells are a critical component to scaling the Marine Coder movement and connecting Marines in the fleet to tools, environments, training and resources championed by Marine Coders!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to working with the II MIG Marine Coder Cell to progress the maturity of software development capability for Marines.  Thank you all the Marines and civilians at II MIG for all the work to make this a reality!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, we expect I MIG and III MIG to be fast followers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">II MIG Marine Coders Cell Established!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2021 NDAA Section 241</title><link href="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/NDAA/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2021 NDAA Section 241" /><published>2021-01-25T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://marines.dev/announcements/news/NDAA</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://marines.dev/announcements/news/NDAA/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-paid-for-programming-skills-similar-to-foreign-languages&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get paid for programming skills similar to foreign languages!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ndaa-2021-section-241&quot;&gt;NDAA 2021 Section 241&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Source: https://www.govtrack.us/congress/bills/116/hr6395/text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;d-education-and-workforce-development&quot;&gt;D: Education and Workforce Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;241measuring-and-incentivizing-programming-proficiency&quot;&gt;241.Measuring and incentivizing programming proficiency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; In general
Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall carry out the following activities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1)&lt;/strong&gt; Leverage existing civilian software development and software architecture certification programs to implement coding language proficiency and artificial intelligence competency tests within the Department of Defense that—
&lt;strong&gt;(A)&lt;/strong&gt; Measure an individual’s competency in using machine learning tools, in a manner similar to the way the Defense Language Proficiency Test measures competency in foreign language skills;
&lt;strong&gt;(B)&lt;/strong&gt; Enable the identification of members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense who have varying levels of quantified coding comprehension and skills and a propensity to learn new programming paradigms, algorithms, and data analytics; and
&lt;strong&gt;(C)&lt;/strong&gt; Include hands-on coding demonstrations and challenges.
&lt;strong&gt;(2)&lt;/strong&gt; Update existing record keeping systems to track artificial intelligence and programming certification testing results in a manner that is comparable to the system used for tracking and documenting foreign language competency, and use that record keeping system to ensure that workforce coding and artificial intelligence comprehension and skills are taken into consideration when making assignments.
&lt;strong&gt;(3)&lt;/strong&gt; Implement a system of rewards, including appropriate incentive pay and retention incentives, for members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense who perform successfully on specific language coding proficiency and artificial intelligence competency tests and make their skills available to the Department.
&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; Information sharing with other Federal agencies
The Secretary of Defense shall share information on the activities carried out under subsection (a) with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of such other organizations of the intelligence community as the Secretary determines appropriate, for purposes of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1)&lt;/strong&gt; making information about the coding language proficiency and artificial intelligence competency tests developed under such subsection available to other Federal national security agencies; and
&lt;strong&gt;(2)&lt;/strong&gt; encouraging the heads of such agencies to implement tracking and reward systems that are comparable to those implemented by the Department of Defense pursuant to such subsection.
&lt;strong&gt;(c)&lt;/strong&gt; Special pay for programming language proficiency beneficial for national security interests
&lt;strong&gt;(1)&lt;/strong&gt; In general
Chapter 81 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after section 1596b the following new section:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1596c.&lt;/strong&gt; Programming language proficiency: special pay for proficiency beneficial for national security interests
&lt;strong&gt;(a)&lt;/strong&gt; Authority
The Secretary of Defense, under the sole and exclusive discretion of the Secretary, may pay special pay under this section to an employee of the Department of Defense who—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1)&lt;/strong&gt; has been certified by the Secretary to be proficient in a computer or digital programming language identified by the Secretary as being a language in which proficiency by civilian personnel of the Department is necessary because of national security interests; and
&lt;strong&gt;(2)&lt;/strong&gt; is assigned duties requiring proficiency in that programming language.
&lt;strong&gt;(b)&lt;/strong&gt; Rate
The rate of special pay for an employee under this section shall be prescribed by the Secretary, but may not exceed 20 percent of the employee’s rate of basic pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(c​)&lt;/strong&gt; Relationship to other pay and allowances
Special pay under this section is in addition to any other pay or allowances to which the employee is entitled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(d)&lt;/strong&gt; Regulations
The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>MARINE CODERS</name></author><category term="announcements" /><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Get paid for programming skills similar to foreign languages!</summary></entry></feed>